<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><xml><records><record><database name="iot-cloud-mendeley.enl" path="iot-cloud-mendeley.enl">iot-cloud-mendeley.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Asimakopoulou, Eleana</author><author>Sotiriadis, Stelios</author><author>Bessis, Nik</author><author>Dobre, Ciprian</author><author>Cristea, Valentin</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Centralized Micro-clouds: An Infrastructure for Service Distribution in Collaborative Smart Devices</title><secondary-title>Procedia Computer Science</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Procedia Computer Science</full-title></periodical><pages>83-90</pages><volume>21</volume><keywords><keyword>Clouds</keyword><keyword>Internet of Things</keyword><keyword>Message Exchanging Optimization.</keyword><keyword>Micro-clouds</keyword><keyword>SimIC</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2013</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.procs.2013.09.013</electronic-resource-num><notes>got the reference from the Cloud4sens paper, as excapmle of device-centric cloud, meaning that thye virtualize the devices and make them available in the cloud</notes><research-notes>got the reference from the Cloud4sens paper, as excapmle of device-centric cloud, meaning that thye virtualize the devices and make them available in the cloud</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Asimakopoulou et al. - 2013 - Centralized Micro-clouds An Infrastructure for Service Distribution in Collaborative Smart Devices.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S1877050913008065</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>In the current information-driven society, the massive use and impact of communications and mobile devices challenge the design of communication networks. This highlights the emergency of a new Internet structure namely the Internet of Things that refers to the transformation of physical objects to smart objects and their communication. Based on that the communication of such objects will offer an augmented infrastructure that is formed dynamically and on the fly based on transient links among objects. This is the concept behind cloud computing, to provide a computer-based environment where various services are available to be consumed by everyday users, anywhere and at anytime. Our vision encompasses a dynamic micro-cloud environment that is formed from devices that share computational power. This encompasses inter-linked smart objects and smart mobile devices available from a smart environment that can be formed dynamically. The proposed micro-cloud notion will be of apparent significance to maintain the required quality of service in dynamic scenarios such as those found in emergency and disaster situations. To represent such system we are focused on the development of such architecture into a novel simulation toolkit that allows the replication of Internet of Things scenarios.</abstract></record><record><database name="iot-cloud-mendeley.enl" path="iot-cloud-mendeley.enl">iot-cloud-mendeley.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Fazio, Maria</author><author>Puliafito, Antonio</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Cloud4sens: a cloud-based architecture for sensor controlling and monitoring</title><secondary-title>IEEE Communications Magazine</secondary-title><short-title>Communications Magazine, IEEE</short-title></titles><periodical><full-title>IEEE Communications Magazine</full-title></periodical><pages>41-47</pages><volume>53</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>Cloud computing</keyword><keyword>Cloud4Sens</keyword><keyword>Computer architecture</keyword><keyword>Data models</keyword><keyword>Databases</keyword><keyword>Geospatial analysis</keyword><keyword>IEEE standards</keyword><keyword>SWE specifications</keyword><keyword>Standards</keyword><keyword>Temperature sensors</keyword><keyword>Web services</keyword><keyword>X509 certificates</keyword><keyword>XMPP</keyword><keyword>cloud clients</keyword><keyword>cloud computing</keyword><keyword>cloud framework</keyword><keyword>cloud service</keyword><keyword>cloud-based architecture</keyword><keyword>computerised instrumentation</keyword><keyword>data-centric model</keyword><keyword>device-centric model</keyword><keyword>environmental data</keyword><keyword>extensible messaging and presence protocol</keyword><keyword>open geospatial consortium</keyword><keyword>sensing resources management</keyword><keyword>sensor control</keyword><keyword>sensor monitoring</keyword><keyword>sensor web enablement</keyword><keyword>sensors</keyword><keyword>software architecture</keyword><keyword>virtual devices</keyword><keyword>virtual sensing infrastructure</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1109/MCOM.2015.7060517</electronic-resource-num><notes>My notes about the paper at
https://www.evernote.com/shard/s36/nl/993099575/45d54219-ab6c-4a9f-9258-d42d87a10f52/</notes><research-notes>My notes about the paper at
https://www.evernote.com/shard/s36/nl/993099575/45d54219-ab6c-4a9f-9258-d42d87a10f52/</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>http://ieeexplore.ieee.org/lpdocs/epic03/wrapper.htm?arnumber=7060517</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>This article discusses two strategies for managing sensing resources in the cloud and providing them as a service. The first strategy follows the data-centric model, where the cloud offers environmental data to its clients as a service, without any knowledge of how data are measured and processed. The second strategy adopts the device-centric model, which enables the cloud clients to use a virtual sensing infrastructure that they can customize for specific purposes. They can access sensed data and customize one or more virtual devices. The article also presents a cloud framework, called Cloud4Sens, that combines both the data-centric and device-centric models, enabling the end-user to choose which type of cloud service he needs. The proposed solution was designed according to the Sensor Web Enablement (SWE) specifications defined by the Open Geospatial Consortium and exploits well known technologies, such as XMPP (Extensible Messaging and Presence Protocol) communications and X509 certificates.</abstract></record></records></xml>
